Freedom begins with an act of defiance
Defiance is a action, drama, history film directed by Edward Zwick.
Based on a true story, during World War II, four Jewish brothers escape their Nazi-occupied
homeland of West Belarus in Poland and join the Soviet partisans to combat the Nazis.
The brothers begin the rescue of roughly 1,200 Jews
still trapped in the ghettos of Poland.
Tuvia Bielski, played by Daniel Craig.
Zus Bielski, played by Liev Schreiber.
Asael Bielski, played by Jamie Bell.
Lilka Ticktin, played by Alexa Davalos.
Shimon Haretz, played by Allan Corduner.
Isaac Malbin, played by Mark Feuerstein.
Defiance is a 2008 American epic war film directed by Edward Zwick, and starring Daniel Craig as Tuvia Bielski,
Liev Schreiber as Zus Bielski, Jamie Bell as Asael Bielski, and George MacKay as Aron Bielski.
Set during the occupation of Belarus by Nazi Germany, the film's screenplay by Clayton Frohman and Zwick was based on Nechama Tec's 1993 book Defiance: The
Bielski Partisans, an account of the eponymous group led by Belarusian Jewish brothers, who saved and recruited Jews in Belarus during World War II.
The film was released in select theaters in the United States on December 31,
2008, followed by general release worldwide in January 2009.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship,
fight, brother, world war ii, forest.
The tone is emotional.